hello and welcome to the 10th tutorial
on how to program in gript 2 now in in
this tutorial I'm going to show you a
new type of variable called a server R
type a server R variable now let's open
level editor and double
click the
NPC and on server side type server
R.T um boat is equal to six
this is a server R variable server R
variables I'll explain in a second let's
close this and
save then
upload if we go to our RC and click the
little flag on the planet icon in the
top right corner you can see all the
server Flags there is a new variable
called server R
dobo server R variables
will work for any NPC and any weapon
throughout the entire
server and well that's about it the
thing is with server R variables is
they're they're a bit messy they
can well it's just it's just if you if
you can it's better off to use client
variables or this do variables but if
you have to you know use a server r.
variable there's also server. variables
but server R variables are sort of like
downgraded
versions sort of like sort of like a
downgraded version of the server R
variable so it's just best off if you're
going to use server R server variables
just use a server R
variable anyway server R variables
cannot be created on client side only on
server side and they cannot
be edited
on client side either you can only edit
and create them on server
side
however you
can use them on on client side as I'll
show
you so I'm going to say hi and it says
six remember these variables are used
throughout the server you can use them
on any NPC you want any weapon you want
it'll always be the same until you
change it or another player changes it
so anyway that's about it for this to
short tutorial and so see you next time